<?xml version="1.0"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">eRouška</string>
    <string name="login_try_again">check the phone number</string>
    <string name="notification_title">eRouška is active</string>
    <string name="notification_title_error">eRouška is not active</string>
    <string name="notification_text_bluetooth_disabled">You need to enable Bluetooth to make eRouška work correctly</string>
    <string name="notification_text_location_disabled">You need to enable Location Services to make eRouška work correctly</string>
    <string name="notification_text_battery_saver_enabled">You need to disable Battery Saver to make eRouška work correctly</string>
    <string name="notification_text_paused">Application is paused. Don\'t forget to resume it.</string>
    <string name="notification_action_resume">Resume</string>
    <string name="notification_text_resumed">Application is running and anonymously monitoring nearby phones.</string>
    <string name="notification_action_pause">Pause</string>
    <string name="notification_action_enable_bluetooth">Enable Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="notification_action_enable_location">Enable Location Services</string>
    <string name="notification_action_disable_battery_saver">Disable Battery Saver</string>
    <string name="foreground_service_channel">Background service</string>
    <string name="foreground_service_alert_channel">Important notifications</string>
    <string name="help_toolbar_title">Help</string>
    <string name="go_back_button">Back to app</string>
    <string name="enable_bluetooth_button">Enable Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="enable">Enable</string>
    <string name="bt_disabled_title">Enable Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="bt_disabled_desc">With Bluetooth disabled, eRouška cannot create a list of nearby phones.\n\nEnable it by pressing \"Enable Bluetooth\".</string>
    <string name="location_disabled_title">Enable Location Services</string>
    <string name="location_disabled_desc">Even though we don\'t use Location data, enable them in order for Bluetooth to work properly by using the button \"Enable Location Service\".</string>
    <string name="enable_location_button">Enable Location Services</string>
    <string name="bt_location_disabled_title">Enable Bluetooth and Location Services</string>
    <string name="bt_location_disabled_desc">With Bluetooth and Location Services disabled, eRou\u0161ka cannot create a list of phones nearby.\n\nEven though we don\'t use Location data, please enable both services in order for Bluetooth to work properly by using the button \u201cEnable BT and Location Services\".</string>
    <string name="enable_bt_location_button">Enable BT and Location Services</string>
    <string name="dashboard_title_running">eRouška is active</string>
    <string name="dashboard_title_paused">eRouška is paused</string>
    <string name="dashboard_body">Application is running in the background and monitoring the surroundings. Please do not force stop the application. Keep Bluetooth enabled and use your phone as usual.</string>
    <string name="dashboard_body_paused">Application is now paused and is not collecting any data about your surroundings.\n\nEnable data collection and keep yourself and others safe. Don\'t forget to do that especially when leaving your home.</string>
    <string name="dashboard_secondary">In case you are tested positive, we will contact you using your phone number %s. We will ask you to send us an anonymised list of phones which can be found under My data.</string>
    <string name="pause_app">Pause eRouška</string>
    <string name="start_app">Start eRouška</string>
    <string name="error_ble_unsupported">Your device does not support Bluetooth LE</string>
    <string name="permission_onboarding_title">eRouška needs Bluetooth to function properly</string>
    <string name="permission_onboarding_desc">Bluetooth is part of Location Services. That\'s why we ask for permission to use Location tracking after you press \"Enable\". Confirm both requests so that the application can function properly.</string>
    <string name="permission_onboarding_desc_2">You are the only one who can upload the collected data, and only when asked to do so by a public health officer.</string>
    <string name="permission_onboarding_desc_minor">You don\'t have to worry: the application is not tracking your location nor does it save it.</string>
    <string name="permission_onboarding_toolbar_title">Permissions</string>
    <string name="login_toolbar_title">Phone number</string>
    <string name="login_desc">Enter your phone number that will be used by a public health officer only when somebody from your surroundings has tested positive for coronavirus.</string>
    <string name="login_statement"><![CDATA[I agree that the Ministry of Health can use this phone number and the collected data about meeting other application users according to the <a href="%1$s">terms and conditions</a> to carry our epidemiological investigation.]]></string>
    <string name="login_phone_number_input">Phone number (mandatory)</string>
    <string name="login_finish_activation">Continue</string>
    <string name="login_code_input">Verification code</string>
    <string name="login_phone_input_error">Invalid phone number (must contain country prefix)</string>
    <string name="login_code_input_error">Verification code was not entered correctly.</string>
    <string name="login_network_error">Error contacting server. Check network connection.</string>
    <string name="login_too_many_attempts_error">Too many phone number verification requests. You can try again in a couple of hours.</string>
    <string name="login_number_already_in_use_error">You cannot use this number.\nPhone number %1$s cannot be used because you have used it for activation on a different device.</string>
    <string name="login_session_expired">Verification code has expired. Check phone number and request a new verification code.</string>
    <string name="menu_help">Help</string>
    <string name="my_data_title">My data</string>
    <string name="my_data_description">This is a list of signal measurements of nearby phones with eRouška in the past %d days. Data does not contain coordinates nor any other personal data. You are the only one who can send the data to the public health officers.</string>
    <string name="my_data_tab_all_title">All</string>
    <string name="my_data_tab_critical_title">Close encounters</string>
    <string name="my_data_column_date">Date</string>
    <string name="my_data_column_time">Time</string>
    <string name="my_data_column_tuid">ID</string>
    <string name="my_data_column_rssi">RSSI</string>
    <string name="about_title">About app</string>
    <string name="about_intro">This application was created under the Covid19CZ initiative. We have developed it with focus on privacy protection so that we wanted to use it ourselves as well. Your data is stored only on your device and your location history cannot be determined from it. Thank you for using the application and we believe that together we will overcome this epidemic.\n\neRou\u0161ka team</string>
    <string name="permission_rationale_title">The permission for location tracking needs to be granted to allow the application work properly.</string>
    <string name="permission_rationale_body">You can find more information about why that is in Help.</string>
    <string name="permission_rationale_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="permission_rationale_dismiss">Dismiss</string>
    <string name="welcome_help">How does it work?</string>
    <string name="welcome_activation">Continue to activation</string>
    <string name="welcome_description"><![CDATA[The application will be monitoring your surroundings continuously and will record all other phones of users with the eRouška application you encounter.<br/><br/>If any of them test positive for coronavirus, a public health officer will call you.<br/><br/>If you test positive, the public health office will contact all the other application users you encountered.<br/><br/><a href="%s">The independent audit</a> guarantees that the application does not send any personal data without your knowledge. Only you may send them and only to the public health officers.]]></string>
    <string name="welcome_title">Thanks to eRou\u0161ka you will keep yourself and others safe</string>
    <string name="login_verify">Verify</string>
    <string name="login_verification_code">Verification code</string>
    <string name="login_phone_number_sms_sent">We sent a verification code to phone number %s.</string>
    <string name="login_phone_sms_timeout">Verification code will expire in %1$s.</string>
    <string name="login_code_read_automatically">Verification code was automatically filled from the SMS.</string>
    <string name="contacts_title">Contacts</string>
    <string name="contacts_suspicion_desc"><b>Thinking you are positive for coronavirus?</b>\n\nStay home and contact your general practitioner or your local public health office.</string>
    <string name="contacts_help_desc"><![CDATA[<b>Do you need advice?</b><br/><br/>All questions and concerns about coronavirus should be answered on the Ministry\'s website.]]></string>
    <string name="contacts_faq">Frequently asked questions</string>
    <string name="contacts_important">Important contacts</string>
    <string name="contacts_improve_desc"><![CDATA[<b>About application eRouška</b><br/><br/>Do you need help with the application or you want to know how it works? Write Anežka, eRouška support bot.]]></string>
    <string name="send_data">Send data</string>
    <string name="data_sent">Sent</string>
    <string name="please_wait_upload">Data was already sent. You can send it again in %d minutes.</string>
    <string name="upload_confirmation"><![CDATA[Were you asked by a public health officer to send a list of phones that you were in contact with?<br/><br/>The Ministry of Health and their public health officers will use the data based on your consent in <a href="%s">conditions of data processing</a>.]]></string>
    <string name="share_app_title">Share application eRouška</string>
    <string name="menu_share_app">Share application</string>
    <string name="share_app_text">Hi, I\'m using application eRou\u0161ka. Install it too and together we can help stop the spread of coronavirus. The application collects anonymous data about nearby phones so that the public health officers can find potentially positive people more easily. The more we are, the better it works. Application can be found at %s.</string>
    <string name="delete_data_description">Are you sure you want to delete your collected data?\n\nPublic health officers will lose the possibility to use your contacts in case of you get infected.\n\nAfter deleting your data, eRou\u0161ka will be automatically paused.</string>
    <string name="delete_data_button">Delete all data</string>
    <string name="delete_data">Delete data</string>
    <string name="delete_user_desc">Are you sure you want to cancel your phone\'s registration?\n\nAfter cancelling your phone registration we can no longer contact you in case somebody from your surrounding gets tested positive.\n\nIf you are the one who gets tested positive, we will not be able to contact anybody you encountered.\n\nAfter cancelling the registration, all the devices registered with phone number %s will have their application turned off.</string>
    <string name="delete_user_desc_unverified">Are you sure you want to cancel your phone\'s registration?\n\nAfter cancelling your registration, we can no longer contact people with whom you have been in touch.\n\nBy cancelling your registration, only the app on this device will be turned off because you didn\'t verify your phone number.</string>
    <string name="delete_registration">Delete registration</string>
    <string name="about">About application</string>
    <string name="yes_send">Yes, send</string>
    <string name="upload_error">Data upload failed. Please try again later.</string>
    <string name="no_internet">Your device seems to be offline.</string>
    <string name="automatic_logout_warning">Your account doesn\'t exist anymore or you were logged out.</string>
    <string name="delete_data_success_text">All data was deleted and eRou\u0161ka was paused</string>
    <string name="upload_data_success_text">You successfully uploaded the data.</string>
    <string name="upload_data_success_description">Thank you for helping against the spread of coronavirus.\n\nPlease collaborate with public health officers to find all the people you were in contact with.\n\nStay in quarantine, limit contact with your family, and obey the orders of public health workers.</string>
    <string name="delete_user_success_text">We canceled your phone\'s registration</string>
    <string name="confirmation_button_close">Close</string>
    <string name="disable_battery_saver">Disable Battery Saver</string>
    <string name="battery_saver_disabled_desc">eRou\u0161ka needs to run on the background, but the phone is turning it off to save battery.\n\nDisable Battery Saver by pressing \"Disable Battery Saver\" in the settings.</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_title">eRou\u0161ka needs to be active even when you are not using it</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_desc">Your phone is automatically turning off some applications when you are not using them to save battery life.</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_desc_2">Enable running applications on background in your phone\'s settings. You can find the guide for your phone below.</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_my_data">Did you meet several people during the day? Check your phone\'s settings. It is possible that the application is being turned off automatically.</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_done">Finish activation</string>
    <string name="battery_opt_label">Application on the background</string>
    <string name="guide_for">Guide for %s</string>
    <string name="consent_warning">You consent with the conditions of data processing is necessary to activate the application. Without your consent, the application cannot work properly.</string>
    <string name="guide_completed">Continue</string>
    <string name="guide">Guide</string>
    <string name="unexpected_error_text">Unexpected error occurred. Try again later. If the error keeps occurring for a longer period, contact our support.</string>
    <string name="data_description">About showed data</string>
    <string name="verify_later_desc">You didn\'t get SMS with verification code? Start using the application right now and verify your phone later.</string>
    <string name="verify_later_button">I\'ll finish the verification later</string>
    <string name="verify_phone_number">verify phone number</string>
    <string name="battery_saver_settings_not_found">Disable Battery Saver manually, please.</string>
    <string name="dashboard_not_verified_secondary">Please verify your phone number so that we can contact you in case you have been infected.</string>
    <string name="data_collection_info">Data collection</string>
    <string name="data_content_info">Here is the history of contacts with other users of eRouška. It doesn\'t indicate their health status.</string>
    <string name="help_write_chabot">Chat with Anežka – eRouška support</string>
    <string name="contacts_open_chatbot">Anežka – eRouška support</string>
    <string name="risky_contacts_title">Risky contacts</string>
    <string name="privacy_header_text">We value your privacy, sharing data is under your control</string>
    <string name="privacy_body_text_1">eRouška doesn\'t have any personal information about you and collects only anonymous data about other eRouška applications in your vicinity.</string>
    <string name="privacy_body_text_2"><![CDATA[<a href="%1$s">Multiple independent audits</a> guarantee that the application doesn\'t share your data without your consent. Only you can share your collected data when administration of public health office requests them.]]></string>
    <string name="privacy_finish">Finish activation</string>
    <string name="privacy_toolbar_title">Privacy</string>
    <string name="activation_error_title">Error</string>
    <string name="activation_error_header">Activation couldn\'t be finished</string>
    <string name="activation_error_body">Check yout internet connection and try again to activate your application. If problems persist, contact us at info@erouska.cz</string>
    <string name="activation_try_again">Try again</string>

    <string name="send_data_body">In case of positive COVID-19 test you will be contacted by worker of public health office. You will be sent SMS message containing verification code for sneding data.</string>
    <string name="send_data_verification_hint">Verification code</string>
    <string name="send_data_button_text">Verify and send data</string>
    <string name="send_data_code_invalid">Verification code is invalid</string>
    <string name="send_data_code_expired_header">Verification code is expired</string>
    <string name="send_data_code_expired_body">Request new SMS message with new verification code from public health office administration.</string>
    <string name="send_data_failure_header">We couldn\'t send your data</string>
    <string name="send_data_failure_body">Check your internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="send_data_back">Back</string>
    <string name="send_data_close">Close</string>
    <string name="send_data_try_again">Try again</string>
    <string name="send_data_success_header">Data were successfully sent</string>
    <string name="send_data_success_body_1">Thank you for fighting against the spread of coronavirus.</string>
    <string name="send_data_success_body_2">Please cooperate with workers of public health office on searching all people you were in contact with.</string>
    <string name="send_data_success_body_3">Stay in quarantine, limit your contact with family and follow the instructions of doctors and health workers.</string>

    <string name="data_notification_content">It\'s been some time since your eRouška updated its data about being in contact with infected users. Connect to the internet.</string>
    <string name="data_notification_close">Close</string>

    <string name="exposure_notifications_off_title">Enable COVID-19 exposure notifications</string>
    <string name="exposure_notifications_off_body">eRouška can\'t communicate with other eRouška applications in your vicinity.\n\nEnable COVID-19 exposure notifications using "Enable" button.</string>

    <string name="sandbox_tek_days_since_symptoms" translatable="false">Days since onset symptoms: %d</string>
    <string name="sandbox_tek_report_type" translatable="false">Report type: %s</string>
    <string name="sandbox_tek_rolling_period" translatable="false">Rolling period: %d</string>
    <string name="sandbox_tek_rolling" translatable="false">Rolling start: %s, refresh %s</string>
    <string name="sandbox_last_download" translatable="false">Last download: %s</string>

    <string name="exposures_title">Risky contacts</string>

    <string name="exposures_nav_earlier_exposures">Earlier exposures</string>

    <string name="spread_prevention_title">Transmission prevention</string>

    <string name="main_symptoms_title">Main symptoms</string>

    <string name="exposure_notification_close">Close</string>
    <string name="exposure_notification_more_info">More information</string>

    <string name="legacy_update_title">Novinky</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_expansion_header">eRouška is expanding</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_expansion_body">We are preparing eRouška to be able to communicate with other similar application around the world. That\'s why we made few changes which we will now introduce.</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_active_notification_header">We support active notification</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_active_notification_body">If you come in contact with anyone with confirmed COVID-19 infection, eRouška will notify you and advise how to proceed.</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_phone_header">We won\'t require phone numbers anymore</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_phone_body">We are canceling phone number register because they won\'t be necessary to communicate with public health office anymore. eRouška will recommend next steps in case of contact with infected person.</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_privacy_header">We think about your privacy</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_privacy_body">With these changes we were able to get rid of terms of usage. The main change being no longer having to register your phone number or any other personal information about eRouška users.</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_button_continue">Pokračovat</string>
    <string name="legacy_update_button_close">Zavřít</string>
</resources>
